Finding Aid for Community Farm of Ann Arbor records, 1989-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Community Farm of Ann Arbor records 1989-2010
Community Farm of Ann Arbor.
0.6 linear feet
2010067 Bg 2
Formed in 1988, the Community Farm of Ann Arbor is a member-owned, farmer-operated Community Supported Agriculture farm committed to biodynamic growing practices. Records consists primarily of meeting minutes, budgets, correspondence, promotional leaflets and flyers, newsletters, and newspaper clippings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated in January 2010 by Community Farm of Ann Arbor (donor no. 10304 ).
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Community Farm of Ann Arbor was established in 1988 as an experiment in Community Supported Agriculture where consumers interested in safe food and farmers seeking financial stability for their farms join in economic partnerships. All the produce is grown using biodynamic agriculture farming methods. The aim of the farm is "to grow the highest quality food possible while at the same time working to heal the earth" (Community Farm Promotional Leaflet, 1991).
During its first few years, Community Farm consisted of a five-acre garden located at 8594 West Huron River Drive. By 1992, Community Farm had moved to its current, 11-acre location at 1525 South Fletcher Road.
The Community Farm of Ann Arbor records cover the period between 1989 and 2010. The collection consists primarily of meeting minutes, budgets, correspondence, promotional leaflets and flyers, newsletters, and newspaper clippings. The collection contains two series: Administrative and Publicity.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Community-supported agriculture.; Community Farm of Ann Arbor.; Gardening--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Organic gardening--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Administrative
  Administrative series documents the organizational structure and annual agricultural offerings of the Community Farm of Ann Arbor. The series contains meeting minutes, budgets, and correspondence.
  - Bylaws, 1992-2002 (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting minutes and commitment forms, 1992-2007, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Board meetings and notes, 1996-2006, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Member communications and offers, 1992-1993, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Fundraising, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
  - 1525 S. Fletcher Road Land, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Community Farm Housing Group, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Biodynamic Associations, 1992-2005 (Box 1)
- Publicity
  Publicity series documents the history, goals, and activities of the Community Farm of Ann Arbor. The series contains promotional leaflets and flyers, newsletters, and newspaper clippings.
  - The Barn Swallow newsletter, 1993-2008 (Box 1)
  - Biodynamic agriculture article, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Community Farm Kitchen leaflets, undated (Box 1)
  - Event flyers, 1991-2007 (Box 1)
  - Fact sheets by Lindsay, 2000-2002 (Box 1)
  - Fall Festival booklets, 2008-2010 (Box 1)
  - Flyers and promotional material, 1989-2002 (Box 1)
  - News articles, 1990-2009 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
    (photograph of woman with vegetable; and photograph of gardening plots)